Kamlesh Chavan

Email Id: kamleshchavan007@gmail.com

Mobile No: 91-8652600007

Website: www.kamleshchavan.com

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE:

I have been working with Microsoft Technologies especially with Dot Net Technology from Sept 2014. I have around 5 years of experience predominantly in web portals designing and development application. Experience spans over end-to-end lifecycle of real time applications such as understanding business requirement, framework design, database design, coding, testing, deployment and maintenance.

CAREER OBJECTIVE:

I am an enthusiastic and professional developer that has enjoyed being part of successful productive teams. I am quick to grasp new concepts and ideas and develop innovative and creative solutions to problem.

To work in dynamic, professional and enterprising environment which will provide me the potential for advancement and increased IT skills, decision-making responsibilities through consistent learning under the business and IT LEADERS.

PROFESSIONAL EXPOSURE:

- ✓ Good knowledge of Dot Net Framework 3.5, 4.0, ASP.NET Core, ASP.NET MVC5, AngularJs, JavaScript, JQuery, SQL-SERVER, MongoDb, AJAX, Html and Css.
- ✓ Basic knowledge of AWS, Jenkins, TortoiseGit, Bitbucket, Git, Git-flow
- ✓ Developed and maintained the applications by utilizing ASP.NET Core, MVC, Web API and Angular with OWASP.
- ✓ A good analytical mind with willingness and ability to learn new technologies.
- ✓ Assigning tasks to team members comprising coding, unit testing and deployment of the applications.
- ✓ Responsible for health checks, unit testing, fixing defects and troubleshooting technical problems.
- ✓ Have provided KT sessions to other teams, establishing ability to share knowledge and take on diverse responsibilities.
- ✓ Have worked on research-based projects with dynamic requirement changes (Agile) and ensuring successful quality product delivery in desired timelines.
- ✓ Actively involved in daily and weekly status stand-ups with teammates, tech leads, Project Managers and Clients.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Programming Languages : C#.NET, HTML and CSS

Web Technologies : ASP.NET Core, Web API, ASP.NET MVC 5 & ADO.NET

Scripting Language : Angular JS, Java Script, JQuery & Ajax

Web Server : IIS

Database : MS SQL Server, MongoDb

OS Used : Windows Security : OWASP

EXPERIENCE SUMMARY:

- ✓ Currently working with **Pricing Innovation Solutions Pvt Ltd**, Mumbai as a **Sr. Software Engineer** from 17st September 2018 to till date.
- ✓ Worked with **LearningMate Solutions Pvt Ltd**, Mumbai as a **Sr. Software Engineer** from 21st March 2016 to 29th August 2018.
- ✓ Worked with KC Group & Aquila BPO Services, Mumbai as a Jr. Software Engineer from Sept 2014 to March 2016.

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION:

- ✓ Bachelor of Science in Information Technology (Bsc IT) (St. Xavier's Collage, Mumbai) in 2013.
- ✓ HSC (Vartak College, Vasai) in 2009.
- ✓ SSC (Abhinav Vidya Mandir, Thane) in 2007.

PROJECTS IMPLEMENTED:

Project 8	
Project Name	Leviathan
Technologies Used	ASP.NET Core 2, Micro-services
Client	Internal
Description	Leviathan is project where all the source data from different excels and xml are
	converted into standard Pulse export file
Roles and Responsibilities	✓ Web Development using Visual Studio.
	✓ Interacting closely with London and India team about the requirements.
	✓ Analyzing the scope of the requirement.
	✓ Implementing the requirement.
	✓ Participating in daily stand-up.
	✓ Integrating and publishing the code.

Project 7	
Project Name	Exim Service
Technologies Used	ASP.NET Core 2 and MongoDb
Client	Internal
Description	Exim service is provides prices and historical data for Pulse.
Roles and Responsibilities	 ✓ Web Development using Visual Studio and Writing MongoDb Queries. ✓ Interacting closely with client about the requirements. ✓ Analyzing the scope of the requirement. ✓ Implementing the requirement. ✓ Participating in status meeting with the clients. ✓ Integrating and publishing the code. ✓ Assigning weekly tasks to the team members.

Project 6	
Project Name	Pulse
Technologies Used	ASP.NET MVC 5, AngularJs and MongoDb
Client	Internal
Description	The GPI pulse proprietary platform offers unrivaled breadth and depth of data coverage which enables fast, efficient decision making and competitive advantage. GPI pulse provides highly granular pricing, access and HTA data down to individual pack and indication level.
Roles and Responsibilities	 ✓ Web Development using Visual Studio and Writing MongoDb Queries. ✓ Interacting closely with London team about the requirements. ✓ Analyzing the scope of the requirement. ✓ Implementing the requirement. ✓ Participating in daily stand-up. ✓ Integrating and publishing the code.

Project 5	
Project Name	SNT 04
Technologies Used	C#, SQL Server, Web Api 2, Linq, AngularJs and OWASP
Client	Springer Nature
Description	This is a tool which is used to provide courses for the US and maintain student
	information and their progress.
Roles and Responsibilities	✓ Web Development using Visual Studio and Writing Sql Queries.
	✓ Interacting closely with client about the requirements.
	✓ Analyzing the scope of the requirement.
	✓ Implementing the requirement.
	✓ Participating in status meeting with the clients.
	✓ Integrating and publishing the code.
	✓ Assigning weekly tasks to the team members.

Project 4	
Project Name	Ace
Technologies Used	C#, SQL Server, ASP.Net Mvc 5, Html and Css
Client	Internal
Description	This is a tool which is used to provide courses for the US and maintain student
	information and their progress.
Roles and Responsibilities	 ✓ Web Development using Visual Studio and Writing Sql Queries. ✓ Analyzing the scope of the requirement. ✓ Implementing the requirement. ✓ Participating in status meeting with the team members. ✓ Integrating and publishing the code.

Project 3	
Project Name	Property81
Technologies Used	C#, Asp.Net MVC 4, Sql Server, Ajax
Client	Property81
Description	This is a online property website for end-user where in they can browse and
	contact seller of the property.
Roles and Responsibilities	✓ Web Development using Visual Studio and Writing Sql Queries.
	✓ Interacting closely with client about the requirements.
	✓ Analyzing the scope of the requirement.
	✓ Implementing the requirement.
	✓ Integrating and publishing the code.
	✓ Understanding Functional as well as Technical Requirements.

Project 2	
Project Name	Havells Power Plus
Technologies Used	C#, Asp. Net Web Forms, Ms SQL 2008 & JQuery
Client	Havells
Description	The aim of the application is to develop online points redemption program for retailers and wholesalers. End user can redeem their eared points with any product they like.

Roles and Responsibilities	 ✓ Understanding Functional as well as Technical Requirements. ✓ Analyzing the scope of the requirement.
	 ✓ Web Development, UI Design and DB Design. ✓ Implementing the requirement. ✓ Participating in status meeting with the team leads and manager.

Project 1	
Project Name	Sampark
Technologies Used	C#, Asp.Net Web Forms, Ms SQL 2008
Client	Havells
Description	The aim of the application is to develop online points redemption program for retailers and wholesalers. End user can redeem their eared points with any product they like.
Roles and Responsibilities	 ✓ Understanding Functional as well as Technical Requirements. ✓ Analyzing the scope of the requirement. ✓ Web Development, UI Design and DB Design. ✓ Implementing the requirement.

PROFESSIONAL PARTICULARS:

Reason for Shift : Career Growth.
Current Location : Mumbai.
Preferred Location : Any.

PERSONAL PARTICULARS:

Date of Birth : 21st March 1991

Marital Status : Single Nationality : Indian Gender : Male

Address : G-05, New Rajlaxmi apt., Narhonha Compound, Cross Garden, Bhayandar West, Thane:

401101.

Hobbies:

- ✓ Trekking, Hiking and Travelling.
- ✓ Playing Carom, Running.
- ✓ Listening to music.
- ✓ Making travel videos.

Declaration:

I, Kamlesh Chavan hereby declare that the information given above is true and correct to the best of my knowledge.